<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>terraform on thedevopscat blog site</title>
    <link>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/categories/terraform/</link>
    <description>Recent content in terraform on thedevopscat blog site</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 14:45:39 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/categories/terraform/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Articles</title>
      <link>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 14:45:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/</guid>
      <description>On this page we will explore some opportunities to enhance the functionality of some basic terraform resources to optimise the efficiency whilst not losing the declarative nature of the code&amp;hellip;DRY is not always good.
These posts will be pitched at those with a firm understanding of terraform basics, looking to raise their terraform game beyond a monolithic main.tf file!
Table of Contents Terraform Count Index Elements Terraform Function Terraform Conditional Expressions Securing Access from a Public IP Bringing It All Together </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Conditional Expressions</title>
      <link>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform4/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 23 Dec 2022 14:44:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform4/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;As you are no doubt aware, Terraform is a declarative laungage, it reads like a shopping list rather than code with a bunch of conditional statements.  I like to think of it as matter of fact, there simply isn&amp;rsquo;t &lt;em&gt;if&lt;/em&gt;, &lt;em&gt;elseif&lt;/em&gt; (etc) type statements at play here and this is a (generally) a good thing.  &amp;ldquo;Do or do not&amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; as somebody wise once said&amp;hellip; (I know my audience!).&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Bringing It All Together</title>
      <link>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform6/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform6/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this series of blog posts, I&amp;rsquo;ve shared some cool tricks and tips I use in my Terraform code.  For brevities sake I&amp;rsquo;ve only ever share code snippets rather than full code blocks or worked examples.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Securing Access from a Public IP</title>
      <link>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform5/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform5/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In this blog post I&amp;rsquo;ll share some tips on how you can securely use your cloud resources from a public IP, such as your home connection.  I&amp;rsquo;ll be using Azure but the principles will apply to other vendor clouds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The specific use case we&amp;rsquo;ll consider is MSDN subscription access, hence the desire to avoid the cost of running a dedicated Azure Firewall, whilst not leaving ourselves vulnerable.&lt;/p&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Terraform Count Index</title>
      <link>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform2/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 15:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform2/</guid>
      <description>As a quick summary, a count index can be used to create multiple resource instances of the same type from one block of code, for example lets say you want a spin up multiple vm&amp;rsquo;s behind a load balancer for some fault tolerance.
The benefit here is you would have one block of code which would be automatically processed multiple times, as specified by your count variable/local, (it can also be set 1 or even zero, but more on this another time&amp;hellip;).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Elements Terraform Function</title>
      <link>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform3/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Dec 2022 14:47:39 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://git.thedevopscat.co.uk/code/terraform/terraform3/</guid>
      <description>Lets start by taking a brief look at the element function, then explore why this simple function is so useful.
We won&amp;rsquo;t labour the point here as that&amp;rsquo;s what the hashicorp help page is for, although sometimes the examples could be better.
The element function looks like this:
element(list, index) You&amp;rsquo;ll note it uses an index &amp;hellip; like our count index in the previous post so we will expand upon the previous example to demonstrate a real would use case.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
